<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Species Conservation on Plum Site</title>
    <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Species Conservation on Plum Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2002 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheetah Decline</title>
      <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/cheetah.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/cheetah.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Genetic uniformity In Cheetah Cheetahs Low genetic variability (LGV) Individual Differences As Artefact of Captivity Behavioural Aspects of Fertility Conclusion   REF: Michele Merola, 1994 A Reassessment of Homozygosity and the Case for Inbreeding Depression in the Cheetah, Acinonyx jubatus: Implications for Conservation Conservation Biology, Volume 8, Number 4 pp961-971
This story urges caution. Wild population estimated 20,000, possibly as few as 10,000. What began as a case of genetic vulnerability became a story involving husbandry, predation and habitat modification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation of Species</title>
      <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/conservation_species.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/conservation_species.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Species Conservation Reintoduction   Species Conservation One of the main players, legally and conceptually in conservation is the species.
Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES). US. Endangered Species Act (ESA). Conservation effort from fund-raising to to recovery programmes and reserve design, dewell on species.  The typological viewpoint follows Plato&#39;s view of species as representations of eternal types (eidos), or, species as immutable creations of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ex Situ, In Situ Conservation and Zoos</title>
      <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/zoos.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/zoos.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Consider... 2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Messages from Zoos 3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Research in zoos 4&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Species in Zoos 5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Education and Zoos 6&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Captive-breeding 7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Questions 8&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Conclusion 9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;References   1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Consider... Role in linking in situ and ex situ conservation. Challenge posed by expanding human and declining wildlife population and eco systems. Conservation of wildlife requires mutually reinforcing links between in situ and ex situ conservation recognised by the convention on biological diversity e.g. for critically small population fragments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reintroduction Arabian Oryx</title>
      <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/oryx.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/oryx.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Pressures on Oryx populations Oman The Arabian Oryx sanctuary Conservation strategy, Saudi Arabia Solutions References   Conservation Aim: To re-establish self-sustaining free-ranging populations Arabian Oryx (Oryx leucoryx).
Pressures on Oryx populations persecuted for trophies and for meat bearing automatic weapons and travelling in motorised fleets. Held captive in private collections throughout the Middle East, led to the formation of a world herd. Bedouin see hunting their right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Species and Development</title>
      <link>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/development.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>plum.github.io/docs/cnrm/species-conservation/development.html</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Challenge: 2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Moral imperative: 3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Development and Change   (Ref: william M. Adams in Conservation and Action ed. W.Sutherland 1998 Blackwell, Oxford
1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Challenge: Scale of human impacts on biodiversity and accelerating pace of species extinction demand attention (see Heywood 1995)   2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Moral imperative: Conservation and development as concepts are often assumed to be unproblematic, looking from outside. Yet the problems, goals and methods of achieving them are not agreed, ad there is debate within the fields, E.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>